# **Austin Fisher** UX Writer

www.austinfisher.me

+1 519-281-6843

austin@austinfisher.me

in linkedin.com/in/stuxain/

## About Me

I'm a storyteller, and I strive to create experiences that make people feel. I use plain (& fun) language to explain tough concepts, and use design thinking to solve unconventional problems. As a UX Writer, I believe I can positively influence people and make their lives easier. All it takes is the right word.

# Work Experience

#### **UX Writer II** Google Stadia (Contract via Adecco)

Feb 2019 - Present

- Owned the content strategy and style guides for the enterprise Partner Experience: web portal UI content
  patterns, CLI conventions, and error strategy touching the back-end, API, and front-end.
- Learned how to read and edit the codebase, so I could understand our system and bridge the knowledge gap between engineering and the UX team.
- Collaborated cross-functionally across product teams and engineering to prioritize high-impact features driven by user research data and critical user journeys.
- Wrote and reviewed all user-facing content across the web portal, CLI, and API.
- Led the initiative to rewrite our file validation errors, condensing 1000+ errors into 50+ error strings, defining new logic with engineering, and documenting all requirements for a smooth handoff.
- Established the UX writing presence on the team, integrating a content review process into engineering and design workflows.

#### **UX Writer** | Sun Life Financial

Dec 2017 - Feb 2019

- Defined user journeys, pain points, and presented findings to influence project decisions facing users.
- Vouched for accessibility and collaborated with translation teams
- Reviewed all user-facing, digital content from marketing, customer relations, and digital design as the UX Writing approver.
- Edited technical content to plain language (customer letters, legal text, product descriptions).
- Wrote UI copy for web and mobile: instructions, buttons, labels, ALT-text, errors.

#### Web & Print Content Creator | University of Waterloo (Intern)

May - Aug 2016

- Designed and edited the Strategic Plan for stakeholders and UW President's Office
- Conducted content usability testing for the department website
- Applied design thinking and plain language to improve the readability of outdated documents

## Skills

- Storytelling
- Design thinking
- Content strategy
- Accessibility standards
- Wireframing, mockups
- Prototyping
- Code & logic readability
- HTML, CSS, Javascript
- Script writing
- Piano & guitar
- Basic game development
- Basic 2D animation

# Education

## Bachelor of Global Business & Digital Arts (BGBDA) - Honour's

University of Waterloo | 2013-2017

- Learned the fundamentals of UX and design thinking
- Created mockups, web interfaces, visual art, video games, and marketing campaigns through a UX lens
- Worked on multiple months-long, Agile capstone projects that addressed real-world problems